airasia.com 2018-12-28

# AirAsia Group Berhad Privacy Policy | AirAsia

AirAsia Group Berhad (“AirAsia”) is concerned about your right to privacy. Therefore, AirAsia pledges to be responsible when gathering your personal information and to protect your privacy in every possible way. Although this Privacy Policy is not a contract and does not create any legal rights, it serves as an expression of AirAsia’s commitment to protecting private personal information.

AirAsia reserves the right to change, amend and/or vary this Privacy Policy at any time and will notify users of the same by updating the policy on AirAsia’s website @ [www.airasia.com](http://www.airasia.com/) (“Website”) and by including a "NEWLY UPDATED" label with the "PRIVACY POLICY" link on the websites governed by this policy for a period of 30 days.

This Privacy Policy describes the information that AirAsia collects, how it is used, when it may be shared with others, and how we safeguard its confidentiality and security.

This Privacy Policy is applicable to all users of our Website including Travel Reservations, Corporate Sales, Marketing Research, Investor Relations, Customer Relations/Service and Customer Support. It is also applicable to all users of AirAsia mobile application and those who provide their personal information during offline transaction at AirAsia sales counters or with third party e.g. our travel agent or service provider and/or any online sites operated by AirAsia.

Information collection  
  
We collect and maintain information that you enter on our Website or give us in any other way (collectively, “Personal Information”). You can choose not to provide certain information, but you may not be able to enjoy all the features of our Website and services provided by AirAsia. Personal Information we learn from you helps us to personalise and continually improve your online experience. Here are the types of Personal Information that we collect:

  1. Personally Identifiable information e.g. Name, photo, gender, date of birth, nationality, passport/identification card number, passport expiry date, passport issuing country and country of residence;
  2. Contact information e.g. address, email address and phone numbers;
  3. Payment information e.g. credit or debit card information, including the name of cardholder, card number, card issuing bank, card issuing country, card expiry date and banking account details;
  4. Travel information e.g. flight information, and currency, departure destination or other product preferences; 
  5. Health information, e.g. health issues relevant to your travel arrangement or medical records and requests; and
  6. Technical information e.g. IP address.

When you interact with applications created by AirAsia or our affiliates, we may collect information about your location and mobile device. The information may be used to provide you with location-based services such as search results and marketing content. You may decline to share your Personal Information with us, or disable location services on your mobile device at any time.  
  
Cookies  
  
Cookies are small files containing information which are downloaded to your device when you visit our Website. We use cookies to recognise your preference information, keep track of your bookings and facilitate site administration. If you continue to browse our Website without changing your web browsers or device’s settings that control cookies, you agree to receive cookies when you use the services on our Website.

Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but, if you prefer, you may set your browser to prevent it from accepting cookies. The “help” portion of the toolbar on most browsers will tell you how to disable cookies.

It is important that you prevent unauthorised access to your password and your computer. You should always log out from your Big Loyalty account after using a shared computer. Click here for more information on how to logout. 

There are 4 types of cookies used on our Website:

  1. **Functionality** : These cookies enable you to use our services. These cookies are essential to enable you to browse our services and use certain features. Disabling them may prevent you from using certain parts of the services. Without these cookies, services like login, booking and paying activity cannot be provided. These cookies also help keep our services safe and secure.
  2. **Preference** : These cookies store information such as your preferred country, language selection and website preferences. Without these cookies, our services may not be able to remember certain choices you’ve previously made or personalise your browsing experience by providing you with relevant information.
  3. **Analytics** : These cookies collect information about how you use our services such as which pages you visit regularly. These cookies are used to provide you high-quality experience by doing things such as tracking page load, site response times, and error messages. 
  4. **Content/Advertising** : These cookies gather information about your use of our services so we may improve your experience and provide you with more relevant content and advertising. They remember that you've visited our services and help us understand usage of our services. Some of these cookies are from third parties that collect information about users of our services in order to provide advertising (on our services and elsewhere) based on users’ online activities (so-called "interest-based advertising") on our services and elsewhere online. The third parties involved in interest-based advertising collect internet browsing information (e.g. websites visited, time of visit) across different websites and over time, and they may use the information they collect on our services to provide you ads (from us and other companies) across the internet.

Use of information collected  
  
Generally, we use your Personal Information for administrative purpose e.g. processing, confirming, fulfilling and completing your transactions and requests for our services. In the event there is flight interruption which shall include but not limited to change of flight schedule, we will notify you via email, mobile chats, telephone call or SMS, based on the Personal Information which you provided to us through our customer support’s live chat or at the point of reservation through our Website, mobile application, call centre or sales counter. We also use Personal Information to provide flight alert messages through AirAsia's mobile services facility and to facilitate online check-in. In addition to this, your Personal Information will be used for the purposes of accounting (billing and auditing), in-flight catering and in-flight sales, marketing or cross-marketing of products and services, investigation of claims and inquiries, immigration, check-in, refund, custom control, safety, security, statistical and marketing analysis, information systems management, system testing, maintenance and development, operational, support, customer surveys, customer relations and to improve and help us in any future dealings with you, for example by identifying your requirements and preferences.

If you have elected to be a member, you will also be a participant in the AirAsia BIG Loyalty Programme which is administered by our affiliate Think Big Digital Sdn Bhd. In such cases, your Personal Information will also be used to administer your membership and offer you the perks which you are eligible for under this programme.

In the employment scenario, we would use information that you voluntarily provide to compare against the job specification / criteria we are seeking / intending to employ.  
  
Sharing of Information Collected  
  
We may process and disclose your Personal Information with AirAsia Group Airlines, our subsidiaries and affiliates and/or third parties, such as credit card verification providers, data analytics, marketing agency, travel service providers, travel-related businesses, partner airlines, airport authorities, customs, immigration authorities, safety and security personnel, parties which have business or contractual dealings with AirAsia and its subsidiaries or affiliates, and other third party who is able to demonstrate that you have explicitly consented to the disclosure of your Personal Information by us to such third party. 

Your Personal Information may also be disclosed or transferred to any of AirAsia’s actual and potential assignee, transferee or acquirer (within or outside Malaysia) (including our affiliates and subsidiaries) or our business, assets or group companies, or in connection with any corporate restructuring or exercise including the our restructuring to transfer the business, assets and/or liabilities. 

Furthermore, AirAsia Group Airlines will jointly use Personal Information as well as cookies for the purposes as described in “Use of information collected” and “Cookies” respectively.

Whenever required by law, we will disclose your Personal Information to the government bodies or authorities or third parties pursuant to a subpoena or other legal process accordingly.

As part of our effort to serve you better, we are constantly enhancing and expanding our services to fulfill your ever-growing needs. In order to realise this business aim, we will from time to time appoint, authorise or contract with strategic business partners. Your Personal Information may be disclosed to these business partners, authorised or contracted third parties, service providers or advertisers to make available promotions, offers, products or services, which may or may not belong to us but relate to the products or services you have elected to obtain from us.

However, to ensure that you will not receive unwanted communications, only information with regards to promotions, offers, products or services which are relevant to your transaction with us, or that you have selected or marked as interested in your member profile, will be shared with the respective business partners, service providers or third parties.

In the circumstances set out in this Privacy Policy where AirAsia shares your Personal Information to a third party, we will ensure that the security measures that such party has in place in relation to the processing of your data are at least as stringent as those employed by AirAsia if not better. This does not apply where we are required by law to pass your information to a third party.

In the event we go through a business transition, such as sale of part or all of our assets, merger or acquisition, your information will likely form part of this transition and be transferred.

AirAsia does not sell or rent any of your Personal Information on our Website to any other parties. AirAsia may share anonymous and/or aggregated information about all our users with third parties.

For inquiries on management of Personal Information disclosed to, or shared with AirAsia Group of Airlines and/or third parties hereunder, please see “Contact information” section below.  
  
Data storage   
  
The headquarters of AirAsia is located in Malaysia. However, we may transfer and store your Personal Information on our servers located overseas. Such transfers are necessary pursuant to our contract with you and/or our contract(s) with the relevant third parties.

AirAsia will secure the storage in compliance with the minimum security measures prescribed under the Personal Data Protection Act 2010 of Malaysia, its regulation and standards, in the following manners:

  1. register those who have access to the storage;
  2. control and limit access based on necessity;
  3. maintain proper record of access and transfer of Personal Information;
  4. ensure all employees of AirAsia protect confidentiality;
  5. conduct awareness programmes to educate employees on responsibility to protect Personal Information;
  6. establish physical security procedures;
  7. bind third parties involved in processing of Personal Information; and
  8. do not use removable device and cloud computing service to transfer or store Personal Information without written consent from AirAsia’s senior management.

Your consent  
  
AirAsia or any third party service providers engaged by us will obtain your consent to collect and use your Personal Information at the time of collection, subject to certain legally prescribed circumstances where your consent is not required. Where required by law, AirAsia will adopt an ‘opt-in' policy to obtain your express written consent when collecting your Personal Information. You may be asked, for example, to sign a form or tick a box.

Generally, in using the Website, you consent to the collection and use of your Personal Information by AirAsia in the ways described above (which may change from time to time) unless and until you inform us to the contrary. You may submit a request to withdraw your consent at any time by contacting AirAsia. If you have provided us Personal Information of third party individuals in your travel party, you are required to obtain the individual's prior consent and you represent and warrant that you had or have their consent or are otherwise entitled to provide their personal information to us. By providing us Personal Information of third party individual(s), you also warrant that the individual(s) is informed of and consents to the terms of this Privacy Policy.

In most instances, it is obligatory for you to provide us with your Personal Information in order to allow us to satisfy your request or provide you with the service that you have requested for.

However, we will provide you with an avenue to opt-out or unsubscribe from receiving marketing, communications, promotional offers, newsletters or any other communications from AirAsia.  
  
Access to and Correction of Your Personal Information  
  
You may access your Personal Information by logging-in to your Member Profile on www.airasia.com. We will need your assistance to ensure that Personal Information you provide to us is current, complete and accurate. If there are errors or changes to be made, please contact us and we will work towards either correcting it or discussing alternative actions with you. We will not correct your Personal Information upon request of a third party, unless such third party is able to demonstrate that you have provided the authority to such third party to work with us to correct your Personal Information.

We will be able to provide you your stored Personal Information upon receiving a request via our [e-form](https://support.airasia.com/s/customcontactsupport?language=en_GB).   
  
Minors* Under 18 Years Old  
  
We cannot distinguish the age of visitors to our Website. If you are a parent or guardian of someone under 18 years old who has provided us his/her Personal Information without your knowledge and consent, you may request that we remove such information by [contacting us](https://support.airasia.com/s/article/Call-Centre?language=en_GB).

* Age of minors for residents in Japan is under 20 years old.  
  
Links To Other Sites  
  
Our Website contains links to other sites (“Third Party Sites”). Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices or content of those Third Party Sites. We encourage you to read the privacy statements of each site that collects information from you before submitting any personal information. AirAsia's Privacy Policy applies solely to information collected by AirAsia and does not apply to Third Party Sites.  
  
Newsletter  
  
By joining the AirAsia email update service, you agree for us to contact you via email to inform you of our latest updates, products and services. If you do not wish to remain a subscriber, you are able to remove your details from the subscriptions list in Member Profile or you may click “unsubscribe” from any newsletter you received.  
  
Contact information  
  
For any queries, concerns or complaints in relation to our handling of your Personal Information or our Privacy Policy, please contact our Compliance Officer at 603-86604333 or email [airasia_privacycompliance@airasia.com](mailto:airasia_privacycompliance@airasia.com).  
  
Our acceptable use policy / website disclaimer  
  
With reference to the terms of use of our Website, please refer to our Acceptable Use Policy for further information.  
  
Our Terms and Conditions of Carriage  
  
The booking and carriage of guests and baggage is subject to the Terms and Conditions of Carriage and Fare Rules.
